What do we talk about react or also about angular and view as a side note we also have to keep in mind
Tepki ya da asal ve grn hakknda yan bildirim olarak konumak iin ne diyeceiz, ayn zamanda
that we can essentially bolt two kinds of Web applications with all these libraries and frameworks.
iki tr Web uygulamasn da tm bu ktphaneler ve erevelerle cebe sdrabileceimizi unutmamalyz.
We can't build a single page application or a multi-page application.
Tek bir sayfa uygulamas veya ok sayfal bir uygulama oluturamayz.
Now what's the difference in a single page application.
imdi tek bir sayfa uygulamasndaki fark nedir?
We only get back one single file byte a server and we get back to fall at the first time to use a wizard
Tek bir dosya baytn bir sunucuya geri getireceiz ve bir sihirbaz kullanmak iin ilk kez sralama yapmak iin bir sihirbaz kullanmak
to page sort of first time to use a wizard.
iin ilk kez de geri dndk.
Exxon-Mobile dot com Deira ofter everything is managed with javascript with re-act the entire page consists
Exxon-Mobile dot com Deira herter, javascript ile ynetilir ve sayfann tamam,
of components which are rendered and handled by javascript.
javascript tarafndan ilenen ve ilenen bileenlerden oluur.
On the other hand in a multi-page application we get back multiple HMO pages where each page has to
te yandan, ok sayfal bir uygulamada, her sayfann belirli bir yol iin ierie sahip olduu birden ok
content for a given route.
HMO sayfas geri alyoruz.
Given you are l we visited for example or come an example the com slash users we get back to different
Verdiin gibi, rnein ziyaret ettiimiz veya bir rnek geldiinde, kullanclarn eik izgileri farkl sayfalara dndn
pages.
gryoruz.
That's important.
Bu nemli.
Now on multi-page applications we might also use react but only to create little widgets.
Artk ok sayfal uygulamalarda tepki de kullanabiliriz, ancak yalnzca kk widgetler yaratmak iin kullanabilirsiniz.
So to say so individually contained components we dump into that page but not the entire page it's managed
Yani tek tek ierilen bileenleri sylemek iin o sayfaya dklyoruz, ancak tepki verdii
by react.
tm sayfay deil.
We also see this on some pages but the more popular approach these days is to single page application
Bunu baz sayfalarda da gryoruz, ancak bugnlerde tek sayfa uygulama yaklamna olan daha
approach because if you manage the entire page with javascript you never have to go back to the server
popler yaklam budur; nk tm sayfay javascript ile ynetirseniz hibir zaman sunucuya geri dnp sayfay yeniden
and reload the page.
yklemek zorunda kalmazsnz.
And that is an amazing user experience because everything happens instantly and even if the user needs
Her ey her an olur ve kullanc bekleyip beklettiiniz halde ya
to wait you're showing a spinner or you're still presenting a reactive web app you're not just showing
da yalnzca bir ykleme sayfas gstermekle kalmayan bir reaktif web uygulamas sunduunuz iin
a loading page or the user can't do anything.
inanlmaz bir kullanc deneyimi. bireyler yap.
So in single page applications our page is bulked up with components and every component is a re-act
toplanr ve her bileen tekrar bir hareket bileeni olur ve tm sayfa kaba
component and the entire page also is managed by a rude re-act component and is just under reacts control
bir yeniden eylem bileeni tarafndan ynetilir ve ok sayfal uygulamada hemen hemen tepki kontrol altndadr. te yandan .
in the multi-page application the other hand.
Tek sayfa uygulamalarnda sayfamz bileenlerle
We also could split up our app into theoretical components but actually a lot of the page is just going
Ayrca, uygulamalarmz teorik bileenlere ayrabiliriz ancak aslnda sayfann bir ksm normal HVM ve C
to be normal HVM and C is US code and some widgets we dump in like an image gallery or something like
ise ABD kodu ve bir resim galerisi gibi bir yere attmz baz
that is managed by react.
aralar da tepki ile ynetiliyor.
So the entire page is not under-react control the individual widgets don't know of each other's existence.
Dolaysyla tm sayfa, bireysel aletlerin birbirlerinin varln bilmedii tepki kontrol altnda deildir.
Therefore in the single application case which is the case we'll cover indice course we typically only
Dolaysyla, tek bavuru durumunda, indis tablasn ele alacaz, genelde, bir kez
have one re-act Dom render call this method you saw in the previous lectures where we trade our first
daha yalnzca ilk kez ticarette bulunduumuz nceki derslerde grdnz bu yntemle Dom render
app.
ars yapt.
Now we only need one because we have one root app component there which is mounted to the DOM which
imdi yalnzca bir eye ihtiyacmz var, nk oradaki tek bir kk uygulama bileeni var; bu da,
hosts all of her re-act components in a multi-page application we would typically call react on render
yeniden bileenlerini yeniden yaplandran ve birden fazla sayfal bir uygulamada barndran ve farkl bileenlerini farkl hale getirmek
more often to render our different components in different places of the app.
iin daha sk ilemek zere tepki verdiimiz DOM'a balanm durumda. uygulamann yerleri.
You saw that react on render allows you to pick a place in your HMO code where you want to render your
aret tepkimesinde, uygulamanz oluturmak istediiniz HMO kodunda bir yer semenize
app and therefore you have these widgets which don't know of each other's existence.
izin verdii ve bu nedenle, birbirinizin varln bilmedii bu aletlerin bulunduunu grdnz.
Now you can build such an application too.
Artk byle bir uygulama da oluturabilirsiniz.
And do you react code you write won't differ.
Ve yazdnz koda tepki veriyor musunuz farkllk gstermeyecektir.
So discours actually covers both.
Yani diskolar aslnda her ikisini de kapsar.
But I will focus on the single page application case since that also allows us to use some libraries
Ancak tek sayfa uygulama davasna odaklanacaz, nk yeniden aktr ynlendirici gibi baz kitaplklar
like re-act router.
kullanmamza izin veriyor.
It is the most popular way of creating web apps these days and all also the approach.
Bu gnlerde web uygulamalarn oluturmann en popler yolu ve hepsi de yaklam.
I can only recommend to you.
Sadece sana tavsiyede bulunabilirim.